

Anderson Araújo da Cruz

SW Engineer, SW Developer, Data Scientist, AI Engineer

B

March 12, 1995

Manaus, AM - Brazil

1

+55 92 99243-6073

http://lattes.cnpq.br/ 2289337100953806

@

ac.andersoncruz@gmail.com aac@icomp.ufam.edu.br

About me —

I've Bachelor's degree in Computer Science from Federal University of Amazonas (UFAM) localized at Brazil in 2016. Actually, I'm Master's degree student in UFAM and research at the Laboratory of Research in Embedded Systems. I'm interested in working in the following areas: machine learning, deep learning, artificial intelligence, data science, embedded systems, mobile applications and distributed.

Skills ———

Arduino, 8051, Galileo Intel, Raspberry

NoSQL, Hadoop, Spark, MapReduce

NodeJS, React

Python, Java, JS, PHP, Android, C and C++

Machine and Deep Learning

(*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

Languages

2010-2012 English

Intermediate

Education

2017- M.Sc. in Computer Science Federal University of Amazonas

Title: Emotion Recognition based on Facial Expressions Using Convo-

Course

lutional Neural Networks

2013-2016 B.Sc. in Computer Science Federal University of Amazonas

Title: Emotion Recognition based on Physiological Sensors

Awards

Best mobile app - Project: Promobile/UFAM/Samsung R\$1.000,00

2015 Best mobile app - Project: Promobile/UFAM/Samsung R\$1.000,00

Experience

2018- Institute Triad Systems - iTRIAD Celetista

Computer Vision and Machine Learning Software Developer

2014-2016 Systems for Behavioral Assessment and Intelligent Recommendation

in Educational Environments and Remote Health UFA

Developer/Research

2013-2016 Strategic program of induction to the training of human resources in

engineering and information technology in schools. FAPEAM- Amazonas

State Research Foundation

Tutor

Complementary Courses

2015 Sentiment Analysis Methods for Social Media WebMedia

2015 Recommender Systems WebMedia

Publications

2017 CRUZ, ANDERSON; LEITÃO, GABRIEL; COLONNA, JUAN; SILVA, ED-

SON; BARRETO, RAIMUNDO; PRIMO, TIAGO. Framework para coleta e inferência de estados emocionais de alunos baseado em reconhecimento de expressões faciais. In: XXVIII Simpósio Brasileiro de Informática na Educação SBIE (Brazilian Symposium on Computers in

Education), 2017, Recife, 2017. p. 997.

2017 ALMEIDA, G.; CRUZ, ANDERSON; CASTRO, T.; GADELHA, B. . Done:

Uma ferramenta de suporte à aprendizagem colaborativa de programação utilizando técnicas do Coding Dojo. In: Conferência Internacional sobre Informática na Educação, TISE, 2017, Fortaleza. Nuevas Ideas en Informática Educativa. Santiago de Chile, 2017. v. 13. p.

//-86.

2016 RIBEIRO, ERICK; BENTES, LARISSA; CRUZ, ANDERSON; LEITAO, GABRIEL; BARRETO, RAIMUNDO; SILVA, VANDERMI; PRIMO, TIAGO;

KOCH, FERNANDO. On the use of inertial sensors and machine learning for automatic recognition of fainting and epileptic seizure. In: 2016 IEEE 18th International Conference on eHealth Networking, Ap-

plications and Services (Healthcom), 2016, Munich. p. 1.

2016 CRUZ, ANDERSON; LEITAO, GABRIEL; BARRETO, RAIMUNDO; KOCH, FERNANDO; PRIMO, TIAGO. Emotion Recognition based on Physio-

logical Sensors and Machine Learning Techniques. In: 2016 International Symposium on Perception, Action, and Cognitive Systems

(PACS), 2016, Seoul (Korea). p. 30-32.